Guide to the Arthur Willert Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, (1907-1920) - (1935-1939) - 1964; Series II; 8' 2" (21 boxes)
  - Books and Reviews
    - Handwritten drafts: [part of Chapter 15] (Box 21, Folder 175)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 16] (Box 21, Folder 176)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 17] (Box 21, Folder 177)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 18] (Box 21, Folder 178)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 19] (Box 21, Folder 179)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 20] (Box 21, Folder 180)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 21] (Box 21, Folder 181)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 22] (Box 21, Folder 182)
    - Handwritten drafts: [Chapter 23] (Box 22, Folder 183)
    - Discarded chapters (Box 22, Folder 184-186)
    - Unidentified chapter (Box 22, Folder 187)
    - Outlines and notes for books (Box 22, Folder 188)
    - Fragments (Box 22, Folder 189)
  - Notebooks and Appointment Books
    - notebook, 1917 July-October (Box 23, Folder 190)
    - notebook: "U. S. A.,", [1917-1918?] (Box 23, Folder 191)
    - notebook: "U. S. A. General,", [1917-1918] (Box 23, Folder 192)
    - notebook, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 193)
    - notebook: "Geneva, Paris,", 1935 (Box 23, Folder 194)
    - notebook: "Germany, etc.,", 1935 (Box 23, Folder 195)
    - notebook: "Germany and U. S. A.,", 1935, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 196)
    - notebook: "Lecturing,", 1935-1939 (Box 23, Folder 197)
    - notebook, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 198)
    - notebook: "U. S. A.,", 1936-1937 (Box 24, Folder 199-200)
    - notebook: "Paris,", 1937? (Box 24, Folder 201)
    - notebook: "Europe,", 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 202-203)
    - notebook: events of 1939-1944 (Box 24, Folder 204)
    - notebook, 1939 October-December (Box 24, Folder 205)
    - notebook: "U. S. A." (Box 25, Folder 206)
    - notebook, 1940 January-1941 December (Box 25, Folder 207-208)
    - Appointment book, 1941-1942 (Box 25, Folder 209-210)
    - notebook, 1942-1945 (Box 25, Folder 211)
    - Appointment book, 1943-1944 (Box 25, Folder 212-213)
    - notebook: "New York,", 1950 (Box 26, Folder 214)
    - notebook, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 215)
    - notes for book (two notebooks), 1965 January - 1966 March (Box 26, Folder 216)
    - notebook, 1966 March 16 (Box 26, Folder 217)
    - notebooks: "People," miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 26, Folder 218)
  - Informational File
    - List of Foreign Office Personnel, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 219)
    - Newspaper clippings: Washington Conference, 1921 (Box 27, Folder 219a)
    - Newspaper clippings re: General Strike, 1926 May (Box 27, Folder 220)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1915-1969, undated (Box 27, Folder 221-223)
    - Magazine articles (Box 27, Folder 224)
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets re: Germany and Hitler, 1934-1935 (Box 27, Folder 225)
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 27, Folder 226)
- Personal and Memorabilia, 1909-1973; Series III; 7 1/2" (3 boxes, 1 folio)
  This brief series contains objects of a personal nature and material having sentimental value to Willert.
  - Identification cards, credentials (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Guest book: Headington Hill, 1928-1937 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Photographs (Box 28, Folder 3)
    See also: box 1
  - Copy of a letter to Woodrow Wilson from Henry White in which Willert is mentioned (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - "The Patriot," a short story with a character based on Willert (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Invitations, programs, menus, 1909-1913 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Invitations, programs, menus (Locarno Conference), 1925 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, programs, menus, 1932-1938, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Willert's obituary, The Times, 1973 March 13 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Set of The Intimate Papers of Colonel House with notes in Willert's handwriting, Volumes I and II (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Set of The Intimate Papers of Colonel House with notes in Willert's handwriting, Volumes III and IV (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Folio
  - Oversize Photographs (Box 31)